Guide to the Houston ARCH (Houston Area Rainbow Collective History) Collection, 1981-2020 MS 569
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Houston ARCH (Houston Area Rainbow Collective History) Collection
1981-2020
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Houston Area Rainbow Collective
MS 569
1.75 Linear Feet (4 boxes)
54.8 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0569aip_001 - MS0569aip_052
The collection contains oral history interviews documenting the history of the lesbian, gay, bisexual and transgender community in Houston, Texas. It contains DVDs of the interviews, written and electronic transcripts, and research materials and bibliographies used for the project.
Historical note
The organization whose sponsorship led to the formation of this collection is Houston ARCH, Houston Area Rainbow Collective History, a seven-member consortium formed to preserve the LGBT past and to improve intellectual access to materials collected by the constituent member organizations and institutions.
The items in this collection are the result of a particular community research project, the work of Rice University students earning credit for the course SWGS 201, "Introduction to Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Studies." Students taking the course from 2007 through 2015 were required to select interviewees from a list of hundreds of Houstonians who have made contributions to the LGBT community and volunteered to be interviewed. Each group of students spent a month researching their chosen individuals. When background reports were completed, they conducted interviews with these subjects and subsequently prepared written transcripts of the interviews.
Scope and Contents
The Houston ARCH Collection, includes DVDs of oral history interviews, written and electronic transcriptions of the interviews, and research materials including newsclippings related to the interviews and the history of the lesbian, gay, bisexual and transgender community in Houston, Texas.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
The majority of oral histories in this collection have been digitized and access copies are available online in the Institutional Repository: https://scholarship.rice.edu/handle/1911/97789
Unedited versions of the oral histories on video or complete transcripts are also available for most of the oral histories via nearline access. Please contact woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Acquisition Information
This collection was donated to the Woodson Research Center by Rice University's Center for the Study of Women, Gender, and Sexuality in 2010-2014. More accruals are expected.
Index Terms
Subjects
Social life and customs; Community activists; LGBTQ people; Universities and colleges
Document Types
Oral histories; transcripts; digital moving image formats
Places
Texas--Houston
- Series I: Interviews A-L
  - Alsbrooks, Ruston: Oral History, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
    - Interview on DVD, 2010
    - IRB form (signed), Wikipedia entry draft, 2010
      Scope and Contents
      IRB (Institutional Review Board) form (signed), and a draft of a Wikipedia entry
  - Atwood, Jerry: Oral History, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
    - Interview and performance on DVD, 2011
      Raw and final edit of interview along with a short performance video
    - IRB form (signed), interview transcript, 2011
      IRB (Institutional Review Board) form (signed), written transcript of oral interview
  - Bagby-Grose, Burton: Oral History, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
    - Interview on DVD, 2010
    - IRB form (signed), background information & potential questions, 2010
      IRB (Institutional Review Board) form (signed), background information and a list of potential questions for the interview
  - Bell, Deborah: Oral History, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
    - Interview on DVD, 2011
    - IRB form (signed), background information, transcript of interview, final outline, 2011
      IRB (Institutional Review Board) form (signed), background information, written transcript of interview, and outline for the final paper
  - Berel-Harrop, Sarah: Oral History, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
    - Interview on DVD, 2010
    - IRB form (signed) & background information, 2010
      IRB (Institutional Review Board) form (signed), and background information of interviewee
  - Brewton, Gary: Oral History, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
    - Interview on DVD, 2010
    - IRB form (signed), background information, transcript of interview, 2010
      IRB (Institutional Review Board) form (signed), backgrond information of interviewee, and written transcript of the interview
  - Briddick, Bob: Oral History, 2018 (Box 1, Folder 12a)
    - Deed of Gift
  - Brines, Nick: Oral History, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
    - Interview on DVD, 2012
    - IRB form (signed), background information, written transcript, 2012
      IRB (Institutional Review Board) form (signed), background information of interviewee, and written transcript of the interview
  - Caldwell, Katy: Oral History, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 14a-14b)
    - Interview on USB, 2016
    - IRB form (signed), background information, typed transcript, 2016
  - Carroll, Tony: Oral History, 2010
    - Interview on DVD, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
    - IRB form (signed), background information, written transcript, and wikipedia entry draft, 2010
      IRB (Institutional Review Board) form (signed), background information on interviewee, written transcript of the interview, and a draft for a wikipedia entry
  - Cloud, Rosemary: Oral History, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
    - Interview on DVD, 2013
      Interview consisting of segments 1-6
    - IRB form(signed), background information, written transcript, 2013
      IRB (Institutional Review Board) form (signed), background information on interviewee and written transcript of the interview
  - Cummings, Delma: Oral History, 2012
    - Interview on DVD, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 19-20)
      Raw and final edit of interview
    - IRB form (signed), background information, written transcript, 2012
      IRB (Institutional Review Board) form (signed), background information on interviewee, and written transcript of the interview
  - Dupre, Ron: Oral History, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 21-22)
    - Interview on DVD, 2014
    - IRB form (signed), background information, potential questions, & written transcript, 2014
      IRB (Institutional Review Board) form (signed), background information on interviewee, potential questions for interview, and written transcript of the interview
  - Feece, Yvonne: Oral History, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 23-24)
    - Interview on DVD, 2011
    - IRB form (signed), written transcript, 2011
      IRB (Institutional Review Board) form (signed), and written transcript of the interview
  - Flanigan, Denis: Oral History, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 25-26)
    - Interview on DVD, 2011
      Raw footage and final cut of the interview
    - IRB form (signed) & written transcript, 2011
      IRB (Institutional Review Board) form (signed) and written transcript of the interview
  - Garrett, Donna: Oral History, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 27-28)
    - Interview on DVD, 2012
      Edited and unedited interview footage
    - IRB form (signed), background information, written transcript, 2012
  - Gullett, Jarrod: Oral History, 2020
  - Guy, Harrison: Oral History, 2020
  - Hammerle, Sean Oral History, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 29-30)
    - Interview on DVD, 2013
    - IRB form (signed), background information, written transcript, and wikipedia entry draft, 2013
      IRB (Institutional Review Board) form (signed), background information on interviewee, written transcript of the interview, and wikipedia entry draft
  - Heinzerling, John: Oral History, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 31-32)
    - Interview on DVD, 2011
    - IRB form (signed) & written transcript, 2011
  - Hickey, Weldon: Oral History, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
    - Interview on DVD
    - IRB form (signed), background information, & written transcript, 2012
  - Hlavinka, Bryan: Oral History, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Interview on DVD
    - IRB form (signed), background information, & written transcript, 2012
  - Hoke, Reed: Oral History, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Interview on DVD, 2013
    - IRB form (signed), background information, & written transcript, 2013
  - Huffer, Sally: Oral History, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Interview on DVD, 2010
    - IRB form (signed), background information, written transcript, & wikipedia entry draft, 2010
      IRB (Institutional Review Board) form (signed), background information on interviewee, written transcript of the interview, and a draft for a wikipedia page
  - Hutchinson, Janis: Oral History, 2014
    - Interview on USB flashdrive, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      Part 1: blue flashdrive Part 2: black flashdrive
    - IRB form (signed), background information, and written transcript, 2014
  - James, Liz: Oral History, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Interview on DVD, 2013
    - IRB form (signed), background information, written transcript, 2013
      IRB (Institutional Review Board) form (signed), background information on the interviewee, and written transcript of the interview
  - Kelly, Don: Oral History, 2020
  - Leo, Januari: Oral History, 2018 (Box 2, Folder 7a)
    - Deed of Gift
    - Conference memorabilia (Buttons, badges, program)
  - Levy, Ryan: Oral History, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Interview on DVD, 2012
    - IRB form (signed), background information, & written transcript, 2012
  - Lingle, Larry: Oral History, 2014; 180799 (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
    - Interview on DVD and USB drive, 2014; 180800
    - Transcription of Interview, IRB form (signed), background information, & deed of gift, 2010; 180801
      Transcript of the oral interview, IRB (Institutional Review Board) form (signed), background information, and the deed of gift
  - Lovelady, Cheryl: Oral History, 2021
  - Lovell, Sue: Oral History, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Interview on DVD, 2010
    - IRB form (signed), background information & wikipedia entry draft, 2010
      IRB (Institutional Review Board) form (signed), background information on the interviewee and a draft for a wikipedia page
  - Baldwin, Shannon
- Series II: Interviews M-Z
  - Malone, Ken: Oral History, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Interview on DVD
      Raw and final edit of the interview
    - IRB form (signed), background information, & written transcript, 2014
  - Manouse, Ernie: Oral History, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Interview on CD, 2010
    - IRB form (signed), background information, & transcript notes, 2010
      IRB (Institutional Review Board) form (signed), background information on interviewee, and transcript notes form the interview
  - McClurg, Henry: Oral History, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Interview on DVD, 2012
      Raw and final edits of the interview
    - IRB form (signed), background information, & written transcript, 2012
  - Oliver, Julia: Oral History, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Interview on DVD, 2011
    - IRB form (signed), background information, written transcript, 2011
      IRB (Institutional Review Board) form (signed), background information on interviewee, and a written transcript of the interview
  - Palomo, Juan: Oral History, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Interview on DVD, 2014
    - IRB form (signed), background information, & written transcript, 2014
  - Peden, Johnny: Oral History, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Interview on USB flashdrive
    - IRB form (signed), written transcript, & deed of gift, 2015
      IRB (Institutional Review Board) form (signed), written transcript of the interview, and the deed of gift
    - Research articles and election paraphernalia, 2015
      Includes newspaper and magazine articles, and a list of endorsed candidates from the Houston Gay and Lesbian Political Caucus from the 1988 general election
  - Robison, Ann: Oral History, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Interview on DVD, 2011
    - IRB form (signed), written transcript, potential questions, & a wikipedia entry draft, 2011
      IRB (Institutional Review Board) form (signed), written transcript of the interview, list of potential questions to ask during the interview, and a draft for a wikipedia page
  - Rook, Sara: Oral History, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Interview on DVD, 2012
    - IRB form (signed), background information, & a written transcript, 2012
      IRB (Institutional Review Board) form (signed), background information on the interviewee, and a written transcript of the interview
  - Salinas, Kristian: Oral History, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Interview on DVD, 2012
    - IRB form (signed), background information, & written transcript, 2012
  - Schroeder, Lorraine: Oral History, 2013 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Interview on DVD, 2013
      Unedited and edited footage of the interview
    - IRB form (signed), background information, & written transcript, 2013
  - Scott, Emma Lou: Oral History, 2015 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Interview and transcript on DVD, 2015
      Video and audio versions of the interview along with the transcript and photos on a separate disk
    - IRB form (signed), written transcript, & deed of gift, 2015
  - Stabler, Meghan: Oral History, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Interview on DVD, 2010
    - IRB form (signed) & transcription notes, 2010
      IRB (Institutional Review Board) form (signed), and transcription notes from the interview
  - Tillinghast, Scott: Oral History, 2014 (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
    - Interviews on DVD, 2014
      Interview sessions 1-3 and final video on DVD
    - Transcription of sessions 1-3, background information, and deed of gift, 2014
      Written transcriptions of interview sessions 1-3, background information, and the deed of gift
  - Tittsworth, Josephine: Oral History, 2012
    Interview in both audio and video formats
    - Interview on DVD & CD, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Media event publication agreement (signed), background information, & written transcript, 2012
      Rice University Media Event Publication Agreement (signed), background information on interviewee, and written transcript of the interview
    - Research: article and written paper, 2012
      Article from the Houston Chronicle (online), blog post from Building Alliances, and a paper written by the interviewee titled: Heterosexual Crossdresser's Quality of Relationships with Significant Other, Family, Friends, and Satisfaction With Life
  - Valinski, Jack: Oral History, 2010; 123651 (Box 3, Folder 8-10)
    - Interviews on DVD, 2010; 123694
      First and second interviews on DVD
    - Pride Festival DVD and list of images, 2010; 123697
      Edited video shown at Pride Festival on DVD and a list of images used (in order of appearance)
    - Transcription of interview, IRB form (signed), background information, & potential questions for interview, 2010; 123699
      Transcription of the oral interview, IRB (Institutional Review Board) form (signed), background information, and potential questions for the interview
    - Research & Bibliography of PRIDE, GLBT Political Caucus, & Houston political developments, 1981-2010; 123708
      Research pertaining to PRIDE, GLBT Political Caucus, and Houston political developments, 1981-2010. Bibliography of research materials and photographs.
  - Van Cleave, Kay: Oral History, 2014 (Box 3, Folder 11-12)
    - Interview on DVDs
    - Final video, DVD
    - Transcription of Oral History
    - Partial interview manuscript
    - IRB (Institutional Review Board) form (signed) and Deed of Gift
  - Walwyn, Des: Oral History, 2013 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Interview on DVD, 2013
    - IRB form (signed), background information, & written transcript, 2013
  - Watters, Dee Dee: Oral History, 2015 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Interview & transcript on DVD, 2015
      Interview in both audio and video formats along with the interview transcript and photos on a separate disk
    - IRB form (signed), 2015
      IBR (Institutional Review Board) form (signed)
  - Webb, Michael C.: Oral History, 2015 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Interview on USB flashdrive, 2015
    - IRB form (signed), deed of gift, & written transcript, 2015
      IRB (Institutional Review Board) form (signed), deed of gift, and written transcript of the interview
  - West, Tye: Oral History, 2014 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Interview on DVD, 2014
      Edited and unedited footage of the interview on DVD
    - IRB form (signed), background information, & written transcript, 2014
  - Williams, Cristan: Oral History, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Interview on DVD, 2010
      Raw and edited footage of the interview along with an electronic copy of the transcript on DVD
    - IRB form (signed) & written transcript, 2010
      IRB (Institutional Review Board) form (signed) and a written transcript of the interview
  - Williams, Tori: Oral History, 2013 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Interview on DVD, 2013
      Interview separated into two parts on DVD
    - IRB form (signed), background information, & written transcript, 2013
  - Wyatt, Carol: Oral History, 2013 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Interview on DVD, 2013
      Edited and unedited version of the interview on DVD
    - IRB form (signed), background information, & written transcript, 2013
  - Melvin, Alexis: Oral History, 2022
- Series III: Project research
  - Bibliographies of research materials and photographs, researching PRIDE, LGBT, political caucus, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 8)